<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./FGDC_Plus.xsl"?><metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>Andrews, SC Hydro-Land Cover</title>
        <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The Hydro-Land Cover leveraged the 2004 Georgetown County lidar and 2016 NAIP 4-band imagery. Because the lidar data was somewhat outdated the process leveraged NDVI and NDWI indices generated from the leaf-on imagery data. Lidar was then used to define the types of vegetation using the elevation, heights, classifications, return #’s, and intensity contained within the point information. Some ancillary data was used to refine water, structures, roads, and bridges at the resolution required to maintain consistency with the lidar and imagery derived features and land covers. Open areas were defined by single return, ground classified points, such that, in most cases, there was nothing above the ground. Of the open areas, two separate classes were created based on the intensity values. Areas with low intensity values were assigned to a paved/exposed soil classification. Areas with high intensity values were assumed to be vegetated, including low vegetation and grasses.For the structures class, the lidar data were classified in a semi-automated process that included defining a base ‘recipe’to highlight structures; it was intended to be liberal in assigning buildings. The second step was to manually remove outlying/erroneous classifications from the liberal, automated first step. Ancillary structure data from cartographic sources were then used to refine the individual structure locations and dimensions. Trees and shrubs were generated from height’s above ground information, which was calculated from subtracting a bare earth DEM from the first return DSM. Areas that were not structures and above 5 meters were defined as trees, those less than 5 meters were classified as scrub/shrub. Surface drainage areas were created from a 2 m DEM using flow accumulation data based on drainage from areas of 4 acres or more. Areas with flow accumulation above a chosen threshold were kept and included in the land cover information. Wetland classes were developed from four of the five main classes (open paved/bare, open vegetated, trees, and shrubs) based on their location with respect to the flooding information, and also from National Wetland Inventory (NWI) defined wetlands. Those in areas with a 95% chance of yearly flooding from the Geoscience Flooding Model (GFM) were classified as river-flooded. Areas outside of GFM 95% area but classified as wetlands by the NWI were considered palustrine and indicative of poor drainage or driven by surface drainage patterns (i.e., local ponding). Open paved/bare and structures in the GFM 1% areas and not in NWI areas were also classified as flood prone locations. To facilitate a higher level of accuracy with respect to the man-made infrastructure manual editing and ancillary cadastral data was required for roads, structures (as described earlier) and bridges, which are difficult to assess in the base lidar data set. Additionally, water bodies and rivers/streams extents and locations were derived from NWI and supplied drainage features (Horry County GIS).</abstract>
      <purpose>The goal of the land cover layer is to map habitats in conjunction with hydro-geomorphic features and highlight and define flooding pathways. In this regard, the basic idea behind the outputs is to produce a “rainy-day land cover product” to emphasize the different hydrologic pathways, flooding drivers, and pooling areas and the types of land cover that they interact/intersect with.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-79.590324</westbc>
        <eastbc>-79.458379</eastbc>
        <northbc>33.473026</northbc>
        <southbc>33.398271</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>Not intended for insurance or FEMA rate maps.</useconst>
    <datacred>National Wetland Inventory data - USDA; Lidar Data - Horry County; Rainfall Projections – EPA; Sea Level Projections – USACE, NOAA;  Analysis - Keil Schmid, Geoscience Consultants.</datacred>
    <native> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.5.0.6491</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Grid Cell</rasttype>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>WGS 1984 Web Mercator Auxiliary Sphere</mapprojn>
          <mapprojp>
            <otherprj>PROJCS["WGS_1984_Web_Mercator_Auxiliary_Sphere",GEOGCS["GCS_WGS_1984",DATUM["D_WGS_1984",SPHEROID["WGS_1984",6378137.0,298.257223563]],PRIMEM["Greenwich",0.0],UNIT["Degree",0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION["Mercator_Auxiliary_Sphere"],PARAMETER["False_Easting",0.0],PARAMETER["False_Northing",0.0],PARAMETER["Central_Meridian",0.0],PARAMETER["Standard_Parallel_1",0.0],PARAMETER["Auxiliary_Sphere_Type",0.0],UNIT["Meter",1.0],AUTHORITY["EPSG",3857]]</otherprj>
          </mapprojp>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000006714873101998366</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000006714873101998366</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meter</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D WGS 1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS 1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257223563</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>VAT_SC_NorthCoast_Andrews_LandCover</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Value</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Red</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Green</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Blue</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Opacity</attrlabl>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20181126</metd>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>