<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./FGDC_Plus.xsl"?><metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>Hindcasted Hurricane Joaquin Flooding Extents</title>
        <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Building flooding surfaces for Hurricane Matthew and TS Joaquin included information from several sources; and included Stream gages (USGS), high water marks (USGS; HWM), tide station 8661070 (NOAA), and deployed sensors (USGS). The coverage of information varied between storms for each source except tide stations. The primary sources of information were stream gages and tide stations. Stream and tide peaks were chosen for each storm and corrected to NAVD and MHHW (tide station). The tide data was used in conjunction with the VDatum (NOAA) MHHW surface for the area by offsetting the surface uniformly. The stream gage data was used in conjunction with a drainage model of the area of investigation. The drainage model was constructed from an 18 m DEM of the area with features representing drainage from 1000 cells or more. The stream gage data was TIN’ed and the elevation of the stream gage surface interpolated to the drainage model. For each line section in the model, the maximum water elevation was used to interpolate a higher resolution Stream Gage Elevation Model. The two Primary Sources were compared and the maximum value used to create a Primary Flood Depth Model. The secondary sources included HWM and deployable sensor information. These information sources are very sensitive to local conditions (rain intensity and drainage). Some of the HWM were surveyed (absolute elevations); some were located with heights above ground, but without absolute elevations (relative elevations). The 2 m DEM was used to define the absolute elevation for the relative values. A second surface was constructed from these secondary sources. The final Hindcasted Water Surface Model was constructed by averaging the secondary and primary surfaces. In some cases there was high agreement between the two, in others there was not. In most cases where there was not agreement, the secondary surface was higher than the primary and the final result tended to be lower than the secondary surface. The final Water Surface Model includes not only typical source derived flooding (i.e., Primary Flood Model) but also includes ponding water so in many cases it would be higher than a hydrodynamic model and represent a worst case scenario.</abstract>
      <purpose>Hindcasted flood extents for Joaquin were developed from measured data captured during and after the storm. Water elevations from stream gages, high water marks, and the NOAA tide station in Myrtle Beach were used to define a water surface. The water surface was subtracted from a 2 meter DEM to define ‘wet’ areas. A bath-tube type model was used with connected and unconnected areas both included. </purpose>
    </descript>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-79.327948</westbc>
        <eastbc>-78.532041</eastbc>
        <northbc>33.960194</northbc>
        <southbc>33.554315</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>Not intended for insurance or FEMA rate maps.</useconst>
    <datacred>Stream Gage data - USGS; Digital Elevation Model - Horry County; Rainfall Projections – EPA; Sea Level Projections – USACE, NOAA;  Analysis - Keil Schmid, Geoscience Consultants.</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.5.0.6491</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Grid Cell</rasttype>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>WGS 1984 Web Mercator Auxiliary Sphere</mapprojn>
          <mapprojp>
            <otherprj>PROJCS["WGS_1984_Web_Mercator_Auxiliary_Sphere",GEOGCS["GCS_WGS_1984",DATUM["D_WGS_1984",SPHEROID["WGS_1984",6378137.0,298.257223563]],PRIMEM["Greenwich",0.0],UNIT["Degree",0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION["Mercator_Auxiliary_Sphere"],PARAMETER["False_Easting",0.0],PARAMETER["False_Northing",0.0],PARAMETER["Central_Meridian",0.0],PARAMETER["Standard_Parallel_1",0.0],PARAMETER["Auxiliary_Sphere_Type",0.0],UNIT["Meter",1.0],AUTHORITY["EPSG",3857]]</otherprj>
          </mapprojp>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000006714873101998366</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000006714873101998366</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meter</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D WGS 1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS 1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257223563</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20180112</metd>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>