<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./FGDC_Plus.xsl"?><metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>Flood Insurance Rate Map Database, Horry County, SC USA</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The FIRM is the basis for floodplain management, mitigation, and insurance activities for the National Flood Insurance Program (NFIP). Insurance applications include enforcement of the mandatory purchase requirement of the Flood Disaster Protection Act, which "... requires the purchase of flood insurance by property owners who are being assisted by Federal programs or by Federally supervised, regulated or insured agencies or institutions in the acquisition or improvement of land facilities located or to be located in identified areas having special flood hazards, " Section 2 (b) (4) of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973. In addition to the identification of Special Flood Hazard Areas (SFHAs), the risk zones shown on the FIRMs are the basis for the establishment of premium rates for flood coverage offered through the NFIP. The FIRM Database presents the flood risk information depicted on the FIRM in a digital format suitable for use in electronic mapping applications. The FIRM Database serves to archive the information collected during the Flood Risk Project.</abstract>
      <purpose>The Flood Insurance Rate Map (FIRM) Database depicts flood risk information and supporting data used to develop the risk data. The primary risk classifications used are the 1-percent-annual-chance flood event, the 0.2-percent-annual-chance flood event, and areas of minimal flood risk. The FIRM Database is derived from Flood Insurance Studies (FISs), previously published FIRMs, flood hazard analyses performed in support of the FISs and FIRMs, and new mapping data, where available. The FISs and FIRMs are published by the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA). </purpose>
    </descript>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-79.339149</westbc>
        <eastbc>-78.540583</eastbc>
        <northbc>34.300004</northbc>
        <southbc>33.571647</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>The hardcopy FIRM and FIRM Database and the accompanying FIS are the official designation of SFHAs and Base Flood Elevations (BFEs) for the NFIP. For the purposes of the NFIP, changes to the flood risk information published by FEMA may only be performed by FEMA and through the mechanisms established in the NFIP regulations (44 CFR Parts 59-78). These digital data are produced in conjunction with the hardcopy FIRMs and generally match the hardcopy map exactly. Acknowledgement of FEMA would be appreciated in products derived from these data.</useconst>
    <datacred>Federal Emergency Management Agency</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.5.0.6491</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>1477</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>WGS 1984 Web Mercator Auxiliary Sphere</mapprojn>
          <mapprojp>
            <otherprj>PROJCS["WGS_1984_Web_Mercator_Auxiliary_Sphere",GEOGCS["GCS_WGS_1984",DATUM["D_WGS_1984",SPHEROID["WGS_1984",6378137.0,298.257223563]],PRIMEM["Greenwich",0.0],UNIT["Degree",0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION["Mercator_Auxiliary_Sphere"],PARAMETER["False_Easting",0.0],PARAMETER["False_Northing",0.0],PARAMETER["Central_Meridian",0.0],PARAMETER["Standard_Parallel_1",0.0],PARAMETER["Auxiliary_Sphere_Type",0.0],UNIT["Meter",1.0],AUTHORITY["EPSG",3857]]</otherprj>
          </mapprojp>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.0001</absres>
            <ordres>0.0001</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meter</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D WGS 1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS 1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257223563</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>SC_NorthCoast_Horry_FEMA_DFIRM</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FLD_AR_ID</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FLD_ZONE</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FLOODWAY</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SFHA_TF</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STATIC_BFE</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>V_DATUM</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DEPTH</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LEN_UNIT</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>VELOCITY</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>VEL_UNIT</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AR_REVERT</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BFE_REVERT</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DEP_REVERT</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SOURCE_CIT</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape_Area</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20180112</metd>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>